Guide to the David Westheimer literary papers, 1940-1997 MS 345
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
David Westheimer literary papers
1940-1997
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Westheimer, David
MS 345
36 Linear Feet (35 boxes)
Contains materials relating to Westheimer's literary work, including manuscripts, typescripts, drafts, reviews, research, and correspondence
Biographical Note
David Westheimer (April 11, 1917-November 8, 2005) was born in Houston, Texas and graduated from Rice University in 1937. He left his career as a journalist for the Houston Post to join the U.S. Army Air Forces after the United States entered World War II. He became a prisoner of war (P.O.W.) after his B-24 bomber was shot down near Italy, He used this experience to shape one of his best known literary works Von Ryan's Express, which was published in 1964 and went on to become a bestseller and a film starring Frank Sinatra. Besides writing novels such as My Sweet Charlie(1965), Westheimer also wrote television screenplays (often based on his work) and his autobiography: Sitting It Out: A World War II POW Memoir(1992). He returned to the Houston Post as a columnist in the 1980s and died of heart failure in Los Angeles in 2005.
Scope and Contents
Manuscripts and multiple drafts with marked revisions of Westheimer's novels as well as teleplays and scripts for his television work. Also included are Houston Post newspaper columns, research, photos, and related correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by David Westheimer in 2003. An addendum was donated by Fred Westheimer (son of David Westheimer) in 2013.
Index Terms
Subjects
Literature; Prisoners of war; American Writers; World War (1939-1945); Authors
Document Types
typescripts; corrrespondence; manuscripts (document genre); clippings (information artifacts); photographs; notes
Subjects (Persons)
Westheimer, David
- Series I: Works, 1942-1997
  - Airwolf: Inferno - Notes (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Airwolf first draft (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Airwolf: Inferno - first draft (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Airwolf - second draft (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Airwolf: Inferno - second draft (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Airwolf: Wild Fire (Inferno) - screenplay (1985) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Airwolf - script revision 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Airwolf - script revision 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Airwolf - script revision 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Airwolf - script revision 4 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Airwolf - script revision 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Airwolf - script revision 6 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Airwolf - script revision 7 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "All Around Man" (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - All the Law - list draft (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - All the Law - second draft; treatment (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - All the Law - revised draft; treatment (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - All the Law - screenplay (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Amazing Penfields - working draft (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Amazing Penfields - first draft, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Amazing Penfields - second draft, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Amazing Penfields - second draft screenplay (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Amazing Penfields - treatements, correspondence, notes (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Amindra Gamble - research (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Suffer Little Children - Sherlock's original treatment (The Most Dangerous Gamble) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Most Dangerous Gamble - 1st draft using Sherlock's original manuscript (The Amindra Gamble) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Most Dangerous Gamble - Sherlock's rewritten draft of Westheimer's first draft (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Most Dangerous Gamble - Sherlock's rewritten draft of Westheimer's first draft (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Most Dangerous Gamble - 2nd draft (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Most Dangerous Gamble - 2nd draft (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Amindra Gamble - revised 3rd draft (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Amindra Gamble - revised 3rd draft (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Amindra Gamble - revised 3rd draft (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Amindra Gamble - 4th draft (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Amindra Gamble - 4th draft (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Amindra Gamble - copy edited (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Amindra Gamble - copy edited (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Amindra Gamble - gallery proofs, corrected pages (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Amindra Gamble - gallery proofs (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Amindra Gamble - gallery proofs, miscellaneous pages (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Amindra Gamble - Author's Galleys (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Amindra Gamble - Author's Galleys (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Amindra Gamble - Author's Galleys (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Amindra Gamble - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Anything is Easy for a Hangman" (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Articles (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Avila Gold - Notes (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Avila Gold - History, Notes (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Avila Gold - Research (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The Avila Gold 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Avila Gold - first draft 1973 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Avila Gold - first draft 1973 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Avila Gold - Draft 2/15/74 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - The Avila Gold - Draft 2/15/74 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Avila Gold - galleys (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Avila Gold - galleys (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Avila Gold - reviews (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Avila Gold - Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Avila Gold - Correspondence, 1975-1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Battle of Montreal - Revolution script (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "The Big Time Edition" (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Big Wigwam - manuscript (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The Big Wigwam - correspondence (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Billy Bett's Last Hand" (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - TV scripts/notes/treatments (Billy's Place) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bricker - Research (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bricker - First and Revised First Drafts (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Bricker - Script treatments, notes (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bricker - notes, drafts, correspondence (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Campo44 - notes, drafts, correspondence (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Contracts - Campo44, The Magic Fallacy (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Campo 44 - 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Campo44: "One Down, One to Go" - Drafts (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Campo44: "One Down, One to Go" - Drafts (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - T.V. Scripts/notes/treatments (Century City) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Cow Babies - story notes (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cow Babies - Research (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cow Babies - Research, Comparative Physiology (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Cow Babies - Research, Cow material (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Cow Babies - Research, Dept. of Agriculture (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Cow Babies - Research, Japan Material, Denmark Solanq (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Cow Babies - Research, Vandenber material (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Cow Babies - Concept drafts (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cow Babies - Drafts chapter 1-6 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cow Babies - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - J. P. Miller's Days of Wine and Roses (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Days of Wine and Roses, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Days of Wine and Roses - Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Divine Providence" (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - T.V. Scripts/notes/treatments (Downfall) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "The Embezzler" (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "The End of Old Hatrack" (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Friends on the Force" (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Going Public, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Going Public - novel (reviews, notes) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Going Public - novel, first draft (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Going Public - novel, second draft (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Going Public - Screenplay (first draft) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Going Public - Screenplay (revised first draft) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Going Public - Screenplay (revised first draft) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Going Public - screenplay, revised first draft (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Going Public - correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Going Public, Over the Edge, Lighter than a Feather Author's Notebook (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "The Ghost of Kegley Vale" (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Golden Triangle (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - The Great Wounded Bird - Corrected Proofs (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - The Great Wounded Bird and Other Poems - 1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - The Great Wounded Bird - Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "The Green Tomato" (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Hard East - First Draft (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hard East - Revised first draft (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hard East (screenplay, revised first draft) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hard East - Final Draft (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hard East - correspondence, notes (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "House of a Dream" (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Hungry Man" (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "I'll Never Go Back to Aley" (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "An Interesting Case" (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Iron Mistress of Malibu - notes (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Iron Mistress of Malibu - research, correspondence (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Iron Mistress - Research, Happy Days (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Iron Mistress - Research, Philadelphia, Los Angeles, Santa Monica (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Iron Mistress - Research, trains (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Iron Mistress - research, The Vanquero (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - The Iron Mistress - draft 12/22/77 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Iron Mistress of Malibu - draft (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - "It's You" (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "Jarrett" (TV), Bob Hope Sample Monologue, Martha Raye Skit, The Pappy Guy, "Plunder Island" Story Outline (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "The Jewels of Ophir" (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Josie - First Draft (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Josie - Second Draft (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "The Kid and the Kitten" (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - "A Killer Among Us" - Rewrite, notes, correspondence, revised (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - A Killer Among Us - notes, treatments-version 1 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - A Killer Among Us - treatments 1 and 2 combined (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - A Killer Among Us - First draft, treatment-version 2 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - A Killer Among Us - First draft, corrected (1984) (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised first draft (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised first draft, 2 copies (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised Jan-Feb 1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised March 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised July 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised October 1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised January 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised February 1989 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised August 1, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised August 14, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised March 1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised April 4, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - A Killer Among Us - Revised final draft April 4-26, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - A Killer Among Us - Correspondence (1982-1990), contract, draft (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "The Ladder of Years" (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Death is Lighter Than a Feather - 1995 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, information (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, requests, and status (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, atomic bomb (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, ending the war (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, field orders (US) (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, field orders (US) (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, historical data (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, homeland defense: Guilian, General, Kyushu, Ketsu-Go (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, homeland defense: Pre-Ketsu-Go planning, Ketsu-Go minus Kyushu, Soviet (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, invasion (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, invasion: Olympic (General, Okinawa) (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, invasion: Pre-invasion operations, pre-downfall planning, downfall (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Japanese forces, equipment, ground, air, sea (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Japanese forces, organization, numbers, dispositions (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Japanese forces, people, living conditions (including civilians) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Japanese forces, tactics, actions, ground, air and sea (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Japanese words, phrases and sayings (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Kyushu: Maps and diagrams, defensive works (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Kyushu- personal notes (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Kyushu: terrain, sea, metro (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Life in Japan: standard of living, morale, casualties, destruction, and other effects of allied attacks (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - summary of interview with Lt. Gen. Indada (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Major Kamed Abe (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Maps (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, Maps (2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, military manuals (US) (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, military manuals (US) (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, military speeches, and press releases 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, notables and individuals (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, other areas (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - photographs of Kyushu (1 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - photographs of Kyushu (2 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - photographs of Kyushu (3 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Research, prisoners of war (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, ship plans (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, significant sites (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, soviet area (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, timetable (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, US forces equipment, ground, air and sea (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, US forces organizations, dispositions, numbers (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, US forces people, living conditions (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - research, US forces tactics, ground, air and sea (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Author's Notes (1 of 6) (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Author's Notes (2 of 6) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Author's Notes (3 of 6) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Author's Notes (4 of 6) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Author's Notes (5 of 6) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Author's Notes (6 of 6) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Author's notes, photos (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Tentative outline of Downfall (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - work copy and notes for Downfall part 1 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - 1st draft rejects, part two, epilogue, of Downfall (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Ret'd work copy, carbons, researchers comments (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - original prologue, first draft (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - first draft (work copy) (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - first draft (work copy) (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - first draft (work copy) (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - first draft (1 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - first draft (2 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - first draft (3 of 3) (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - First Draft (xerox) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Original Prologue (second draft) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Second Draft (1 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Second Draft (2 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Second Draft (3 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Final Draft (work copy) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Final Draft (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Printer's Copy (1 of 4) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Printer's Copy (2 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Printer's Copy (3 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Printer's Copy (4 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Proof (American Edition) (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Proof (American Edition) (2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Proof (British Edition) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Reviews, Publicity, Southwest writers Conference (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Comments from Japan (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Lighter Than a Feather -Correspondence (1968-1982) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "A" (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "B" (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "C", "D" (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "Dr. A. Cox" (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "Diaz, Noel, E, F, G" (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "H" Hamilburg Agency, Col. Holland (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "I, J, Michael Joseph Ltd." (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "K" (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "L", Little Brown Company (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "M, N, O" (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "P, Barry P.H, Q" (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "R" (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "S, T" (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "Rose Sayers" (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "AL Snook" (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "Roslyn Targ Agency, U" (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - Correspondence "V, W, X, Y, Z" (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lighter Than a Feather - miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Lone Star Zodiac, 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - "The Long Minute" (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - The Lost Boy - Lucan - notes, writer's guide, correspondence (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - The Lost Boy - Lucan - 1st draft of story, story outline (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - The Lost Boy - Lucan - Rough Draft (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - The Lost Boy - Lucan - Work Draft (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - The Lost Boy - Lucan - 1st draft (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - The Lost Boy - Lucan - 2nd draft; Final draft (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - The Lost Boy - Lucan - Revisions (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Macready and the Chance (novel) (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - The Magic Fallacy - 1949-1950 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - The Magic Fallacy - original manuscript (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - The Magic Fallacy - Alley Theatre version (1950) (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - The Magic Fallacy (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - The Magic Fallacy - 1st draft (mid-50's) (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - The Magic Fallacy - 2nd draft (mid-50's) (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - The Magic Fallacy - Reviews (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - The Magic Fallacy - Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Mimosa Place - "Our House" Notes (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Mimosa Place - "Our House" (original 1st draft) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Mimosa Place - "Our House" (revised 1st draft, 2 copies) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Mimosa Place - "Our House" (2nd draft revisions, final draft) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Mr. Jonathan - T.V. Series; "A Stone, an Ant, a Grain of Sand"; "My Father, My Enemy"; "Johnny Nobody"; "Homo Aquaticus" (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Mr. Smoon" (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "My Mother" (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - My Sweet Charlie (novel) - 1965-67, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - My Sweet Charlie (novel) - 1st draft with notes (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - My Sweet Charlie (novel) - 2nd draft (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - My Sweet Charlie (novel) - printer's copy (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - My Sweet Charlie (novel) - Galley proof (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - My Sweet Charlie (novel) - Galley proof (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - n.d. and memorabilia (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - dialogue extract from novel (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - 1st draft (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - 1st draft (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - 2nd draft (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - 3rd draft (1 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - 3rd draft (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - final draft (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - 1st act revisions (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - 3rd act revisions (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - working cop (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - working copy for rehearsals and try-outs (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - master copy (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - publicity and miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - schedules; preview notes, polls; playbills (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - reviews, notes (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - My Sweet Charlie (play) - correspondence and reviews (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - My Sweet Charlie (novel and play) - correspondence 1969-1974 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - My Sweet Charlie - Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - My Sweet Charlie - Correspondence (including fan mail) (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - My Sweet Charlie - Correspondence (including fan mail) (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Contracts: My Sweet Charlie, Song of the Young Sentry, Von Ryan's Express (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "Nicholas" (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "Nuts to Ingeborg" (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "Old Man Clinton's Cat" (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Olmec Head, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Olmec Head - Research (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - The Olmec Head - Research, Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Olmec Head - Research, Maps (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - The Olmec Head - 1st draft (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - The Olmec Head - 1st draft (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - The Olmec Head - 3rd draft (1 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - The Olmec Head - 3rd draft (2 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - The Olmec Head - 3rd draft (3 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - The Olmec Head - Copy editor's queries (1973) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Olmec Head - Printer's Copy (1 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Olmec Head - Printer's Copy (2 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 3)